Title 50 CFR: Wildlife and Fisheries
PART 622 FISHERIES OF THE CARIBBEAN, GULF OF MEXICO, AND SOUTH ATLANTIC
Subpart B – Reef Fish Resources of the Gulf of Mexico
§ 622.35 Gear restricted areas.

(d) Alabama SMZ. The Alabama SMZ consists of artificial reefs and surrounding areas. 
In the Alabama SMZ, fishing by a vessel that is operating as a charter vessel or headboat, 
a vessel that does not have a commercial permit for Gulf reef fish, as required under §622.20(a)(1),
 or a vessel with such a permit fishing for Gulf reef fish is limited to hook-and-line gear with 
three or fewer hooks per line and spearfishing gear. A person aboard a vessel that uses on any 
trip gear other than hook-and-line gear with three or fewer hooks per line and spearfishing gear
in the Alabama SMZ is limited on that trip to the bag limits for Gulf reef fish specified in §622.38(b)
 and, for Gulf reef fish for which no bag limit is specified in §622.38(b), the vessel is limited to 5 percent,
 by weight, of all fish on board or landed. The Alabama SMZ is bounded by rhumb lines connecting, in order,
 the following points:

---------------------------------------------------------
Point                       North lat.   West long.
---------------------------------------------------------
A.......................... 30°02.5'     88°07.7'
B.......................... 30°02.6'     87°59.3'
C.......................... 29°55.0'     87°55.5'
D.......................... 29°54.5'     88°07.5'
A.......................... 30°02.5'     88°07.7'
---------------------------------------------------------