Title 50 CFR: Wildlife and Fisheries
PART 622 FISHERIES OF THE CARIBBEAN, GULF OF MEXICO, AND SOUTH ATLANTIC
Subpart B—Reef Fish Resources of the Gulf of Mexico
§ 622.35 Gear restricted areas.

(a) Reef fish stressed area. The stressed area is that part of the Gulf EEZ shoreward of 
rhumb lines connecting, in order, the points listed in Table 2 in Appendix B of this part.

(1) A powerhead may not be used in the stressed area to take Gulf reef fish. Possession 
of a powerhead and a mutilated Gulf reef fish in the stressed area or after having fished 
in the stressed area constitutes prima facie evidence that such reef fish was taken with a 
powerhead in the stressed area. The provisions of this paragraph do not apply to hogfish.

(2) A roller trawl may not be used in the stressed area. Roller trawl means a trawl net 
equipped with a series of large, solid rollers separated by several smaller spacer rollers 
on a separate cable or line (sweep) connected to the footrope, which makes it possible to 
fish the gear over rough bottom, that is, in areas unsuitable for fishing conventional 
shrimp trawls. Rigid framed trawls adapted for shrimping over uneven bottom, in wide use 
along the west coast of Florida, and shrimp trawls with hollow plastic rollers for fishing 
on soft bottoms, are not considered roller trawls.

Table 2 of Appendix B to Part 622—Seaward Coordinates of the Stressed Area
------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Point No. and reference location \1\
                                    North lat.   West long.
------------------------------------------------------------------------
1 Seaward limit of Florida's         24°45.5'     82°41.5'
 waters northeast of Dry Tortugas.
2 North of Marquesas Keys.........   24°48.0'     82°06.5'
3 Off Cape Sable..................   25°15.0'     82°02.0'
4 Off Sanibel Island_Inshore......   26°26.0'     82°29.0'
5 Off Sanibel Island_Offshore.....   26°26.0'     82°59.0'
6 West of Egmont Key..............   27°30.0'     83°21.5'
7 Off Anclote Keys_Offshore.......   28°10.0'     83°45.0'
8 Off Anclote Keys_Inshore........   28°10.0'     83°14.0'
9 Off Deadman Bay.................   29°38.0'     84°00.0'
10 Seaward limit of Florida's        29°35.5'     84°38.6'
 waters east of Cape St. George...
Thence westerly along the seaward
 limit of Florida's waters to: 
11 Seaward limit of Florida's        29°32.2'     85°27.1'
 waters south of Cape San Blas....
12 Southwest of Cape San Blas.....   29°30.5'     85°52.0'
13 Off St. Andrew Bay.............   29°53.0'     86°10.0'
14 De Soto Canyon.................   30°06.0'     86°55.0'
15 South of Florida/Alabama border   29°34.5'     87°38.0'
16 Off Mobile Bay.................   29°41.0'     88°00.0'
17 South of Alabama/Mississippi      30°01.5'     88°23.7'
 border...........................
18 Horn/Chandeleur Islands........   30°01.5'     88°40.5'
19 Chandeleur Islands.............   29°35.5'     88°37.0'
20 Seaward limit of Louisiana's      29°16.3'     89°00.0'
 waters off North Pass of the
 Mississippi River................
Thence southerly and westerly
 along the seaward limit of
 Louisiana's waters to:
21 Seaward limit of Louisiana's      28°57.3'     89°28.2'
 waters off Southwest Pass of the
 Mississippi River................
22 Southeast of Grand Isle........   29°09.0'     89°47.0'
23 Quick flashing horn buoy south    28°32.5'     90°42.0'
 of Isles Dernieres...............
24 Southeast of Calcasieu Pass....   29°10.0'     92°37.0'
25 South of Sabine Pass_10 fathoms   29°09.0'     93°41.0'
26 South of Sabine Pass_30 fathoms   28°21.5'     93°28.0'
27 East of Aransas Pass...........   27°49.0'     96°19.5'
28 East of Baffin Bay.............   27°12.0'     96°51.0'
29 Northeast of Port Mansfield....   26°46.5'     96°52.0'
30 Northeast of Port Isabel.......   26°21.5'     96°35.0'
31 U.S./Mexico EEZ boundary.......   26°00.5'     96°36.0'
Thence westerly along U.S./Mexico
 EEZ boundary to the seaward limit
 of Texas' waters ................
------------------------------------------------------------------------
\1\ Nearest identifiable landfall, boundary, navigational aid, or
  submarine area.